And welcome once more to our favorite place to be Jupyter Lab, the Paradise for a data scientist experimenter.
다시 한번 환영합니다 이곳은 우리가 가장 좋아하는 유피터 연구소입니다 데이터 과학자 실험자의 천국이죠
So as we launch into the day three notebook in week eight, you'll see that there are precious few comments
8주 차에 나온 셋째 날 공책을 보면 이번에는 댓글이 거의 없는 걸 볼 수
this time around.
있어요
I'm commenting the code that is our production quality code in the notebooks.
생산 품질의 코드를 공책에 적었어요
At this point.
지금은요
You guys are pros.
두 분은 프로예요
You don't need a whole ton of waffle from me, so we just dive straight in.
와플을 많이 먹을 필요는 없어요 바로 시작하죠
Uh, so I'm going to begin with some imports.
몇 가지 수입품부터 시작할게요
As we get into today's puzzle, uh, I'm going to set up some environment things, and now we get to
오늘 퍼즐을 풀려면 환경 설정부터 해야 해요 그럼 첫 번째 퍼즐 조각을
the first piece of substance.
맞춰 보죠 get it
Uh, I, uh, sneakily imported something called Scraped deal, uh, here without mentioning it, but
제가 Scraped 딜이라는 걸 몰래 수입했어요 언급하지 않고서요 어쨌든
I now have this scraped deal, and I'm going to call fetch.
이 스크랩드 딜이 있으니 불러올게요
Um, with setting show progress to true, and I'm going to run that without telling you what it does,
Show Properue를 true로 설정합니다 뭘 하는지는 말 안 하고
because it takes a couple of minutes, so we might as well let it run.
실행할게요 몇 분 걸리니까요 그냥 실행하죠
And then I will talk more about it.
그 후에 더 얘기할게요
So kick it off.
그럼 시작하죠
Off it goes.
출발해요
So what is scraped?
뭘 긁어내죠?
Deal.
좋아요
It is sitting in the agents folder in the package.
패키지 안의 에이전트 폴더에 있어요
And here is it is in part of deals dot pie.
할인 닷 파이에 나와 있어요
So let me show you deals dot pie.
할인 닷 파이를 보여드릴게요
So uh, this is a Python module which starts by defining a series of feeds.
이건 파이썬 으로 구성된 모듈입니다 피드들을 정의하는 것으로 시작을 하죠
And these are URLs to RSS feeds, which are useful ones that happen to have good deals being announced
URL에서 RSS로의 피드입니다 좋은 거래가 다양한 카테고리로 발표되는 유용한
in a various categories.
것들이죠
And these categories happen to be close matches for the categories that we know a thing or two about
이 부문들은 우리가 잘 아는 부문과 막상막하입니다 우리 모델은
because our model was trained for them electronics, computers, automotive, and then mostly smart
전자제품 컴퓨터, 자동차 그리고 스마트 홈 가든 부문에서 훈련받았거든요
So here are some feeds.
여기 영상이 있어요
There are a bunch of others, and if you have the stomach to wait a bit longer, you can slap in a bunch
다른 것도 많아요 좀 더 기다릴 배짱이 있다면 여기에 비트를
more feeds in here and have a bigger data set to work with.
잔뜩 추가해 작업할 데이터 모음이 커지죠
So then there are some utilities here that you can look through in your own time.
여기 몇 가지 유틸리티가 있는데 여러분이 원할 때 살펴볼 수 있어요
A method called extract, a function called extract, which cleans up some HTML and returns useful text.
추출물이라는 메서드와 함수가 있는데 HTML을 청소하고 유용한 텍스트를 반환하죠
And then there's a class scraped deal.
그리고 학급 간의 마찰도 있죠
And this represents a deal that we have retrieved from an RSS feed.
이건 RSS 피드에서 회수한 거래예요
So it's not exactly scraping, it's retrieving it from RSS.
긁는 게 아니라 RSS에서 회수하는 거군요
But we will do a bit of a of a lookup as well.
비트 박스도 좀 살펴볼 거예요
So so there's there's some truth to it.
어느 정도 사실인 거죠
Um, what we do in the init we take something called an entry, which is just a dictionary of values.
init에서 하는 일은 항목이라는 걸 갖는 거예요 그냥 값의 사전이죠
And we're going to pass in.
우린 통과할 거예요
And this is something we get straight from the RSS feed.
RSS 피드에서 바로 얻을 수 있는 정보죠
And what we do is we pick the title, the summary, and we take the links.
우리가 하는 일은 제목과 요약을 고르고 링크를 가져오는 거죠
And then if you look at here, what we do here is we take its URL and we actually go and fetch that.
여길 보시면 URL을 갖고 그걸 페치하는 거죠
So we do are doing some scraping here.
그래서 긁어내고 있어요
Sorry.
미안해요
We do some some fetching of that URL and we put the results in stuff and then we parse stuff with beautiful
URL 페치잉을 하고 그 결과들을 입력하고 멋진 put으로 그걸 분석하죠
soup.
첫째 주에 했던 것과 유사하죠 요청에서 검색한 URL 파싱
from Requests.get.
때요 get이요.
Okay.
네
And then there's some more stuff here that takes the contents and scrubs it.
그리고 내용물을 스크럽하는 것도 있어요
And then we potentially build some features if we have the features.
그런 다음 기능이 있다면 일부 기능을 구축하죠
So this is all a bit of, uh, scraping code to be able to take something that comes in an RSS feed,
RSS 비트로 들어온 걸 깨끗하게 청소해서 레코드로 만드는 건
clean it up and turn it into a record.
다 긁어내는 코드예요
Um, and then there's something that prints what it is.
그리고 인쇄하는 것도 있어요
And this class method fetch, is exactly the one that we just kicked off a moment ago that you can see
이 클래스 메서드 페치는 조금 전에 시작한 것으로 실행이 끝난 걸
has finished running.
보실 수 있죠
Uh, and what it does is it iterates through all of the feeds, um, and it calls something called feed
하는 일은 모든 피드를 반복하는 겁니다 피드 파서라는 걸 호출하죠
And feedparser is a package that I've imported, which is a useful package that allows you to pull RSS
파즈예요
feeds and it will give them to you as a dictionary.
사전으로서 그걸 줘요
So we are using Feedparser as our Python package for doing this, and we're just taking the top ten
파이썬 패키지로 Feedparer를 이용하고 있습니다 각각의 피드에서 가져온 상위
that comes back from each of these different feeds.
10개만 가지고 올 수 있죠
We take the top ten deals that we get from each one.
Get in get it up
And of course this is something where you can choose to bring back more data if you wish.
물론 원한다면 더 많은 데이터를 가져올 수도 있어요
For the moment, I'm just constraining it to that number.
지금은 그냥 그 숫자에 묶을게요
And then for each of them we create this is this is ourselves.
각각의 캐릭터는 이게 우리 자신이에요
We create an instance of us, uh, for that entry.
그 항목을 위해 우리에 대한 예를 만들죠
That entry, of course, is the dictionary that we looked at a moment ago.
그 항목은 물론 우리가 방금 본 사전이죠
Um, and there's a little time.sleep in here, if you're wondering about that.
시간이 좀 있어요 혹시 궁금하다면 여기서 자요
Uh, that's because I figured that since we're then going and doing a get to to retrieve that web page
할인 웹사이트에서 웹 페이지를 검색하러 get to를 하는
from this deals website, it was antisocial.
거니까 반사회적이라고 생각했거든요
If we hammer that website with tons of requests, one after another with a split second between them.
수많은 요청이 들어온 그 웹사이트를 공격하면 짧은 시간 안에 하나씩 차례로 올라올 거예요
So it's considered good scraping practices to put in a sleep so that you're not overly, uh, beating
웹 서버를 너무 혹사하거나 너무 많은 것을 요구하지 않도록 get 절약을
up a web server and being too needy.
하는 것이 좋은 방법이죠.
So this is a way of us being better citizens when we retrieve these deals from the websites, and then
우리가 웹사이트에서 이런 계약을 회수하면 더 나은 시민이
it returns those deals.
되는 거죠
So that's what I just did.
그래서 그렇게 했어요
And those deals should be sitting waiting for us in this notebook.
그 거래들이 이 공책에 담겨 있어야 해요
But I will first just mention a couple of other things in this useful module.
하지만 먼저 이 유용한 모듈에서 몇 가지 다른 걸 언급할게요
Um, there are these three classes here that are going to be important in a minute because this is how
여기 세 가지 강좌가 있는데 잠시 후에 중요하게 다룰 거예요 구조화된 출력물들을
we define structured outputs.
어떻게 정의하는지 보여주거든요
When we ask GPT four to respond, um, we are defining here a class deal, a class deal selection and
GPT 4에 답변을 요청할 때 클래스 딜을 정의하고 있습니다 클래스 딜 선택과 클래스
then a class opportunity.
기회죠
And you can see that these are subclasses of base model.
이게 기본 모델의 서브클래스인 게 보이시죠
Base model is uh, comes from the Pydantic package, which does a number of different things.
베이스 모델은 파이댄틱 패키지에서 나온 건데 여러 가지 기능이 있어요
One of the things it does is it very easily allows you to switch between JSON versions of of a class
그 중 하나는 아주 쉽게 클래스의 JSON 버전과 그 구조, 클래스 자체를 전환할 수 있게 해줍니다
and its structure and the class itself, and it also is able to enforce that a class adheres to a schema.
또한 클래스가 스키마에 충실하도록 시행할 수도 있어요
So there's a lot about it that probably many of you are very familiar with.
여러분 중 많은 분이 아주 익숙하실 거예요
Pedantic.
현학적이군요
Um, but but all you need to do to use it is simply create a new class that is a subclass of base model.
하지만 그걸 사용하려면 기본 모델의 서브클래스인 새 클래스를 생성하면 돼요
So our first class that we define is just called a deal.
첫 번째 클래스는 거래라고 불러요
And it is something which just has a product description, a price and a URL.
제품 설명, 가격, URL 같은 것만 있는 거죠
That's it description price URL.
설명 가격 URL 예요
And then we have another thing called deal selection.
거래 선택이라는 것도 있어요
And this is what we're going to ask GPT four to respond with.
GPT 4에 대응하라고 요청할 거예요
We're going to tell it we want a deal selection.
우린 거래를 원한다고 말할 거예요
So this is the important one.
이게 중요한 거예요
And it's very simple.
아주 간단해요
It's just something that has a list of these deals in a single attribute called deals.
딜이라고 부르는 단일 특성에 이런 딜의 리스트를 가진 뭔가죠
That's that's all there is to it.
그게 다인 것 같아요
So deal selection means I want a list of deal objects.
딜 선택은 딜 객체의 리스트를 원한다는 뜻이죠
So if you think of this in your mind in JSON speak, what?
JSON 스피커로 이걸 생각해보면 뭐죠?
What this will look like in JSON terms is it's going to be like this deal selection is a single object
JSON 용어에서 이건 이런 모습입니다 이 딜 선택은 하나의 객체로
which only has one attribute deals.
오직 하나의 특성 딜을 갖고 있죠
And that is a list.
그게 목록이에요
And it's a list of things which are each objects.
각각의 개체들의 목록이죠
So when that goes into JSON it will look like this.
JSON으로 가면 이렇게 보일 거예요
It has a product description.
제품 설명도 있어요
And it has a price which is a float.
가격표는 플로트라고 해요
And it has a URL which is a some kind of a.
URL 같은 것도 있고요
URL like so uh, and that makes a deal.
URL 같은 거요 그럼 거래가 성사되죠
And there is a whole bunch of them potentially in a list of deals.
아마 목록에 그런 게 아주 많을 거예요
And that makes up a deal selection.
그럼 거래 선택이 완성되죠
So if you look at the JSON that I just typed there and compare it to these class definitions, I hope
제가 방금 입력한 JSON을 보시면 이 클래스 정의와 비교해 보세요
it becomes clearer in your mind how they are analogous to each other.
서로 어떻게 유사한지 더 명확해지길 바라요
This is just the JSON representation of this structure here.
이건 이 구조의 JSON 표현이에요
And indeed, when we say to GPT four, we want the structured output to be in this format, what we're
GPT 4에 구조화된 출력이 이 포맷에 있길 원한다고 할 때 여러분이
kind of doing is saying we want this to be the kind of JSON that you respond with.
응답하는 일종의 JSON이 되길 원한다고 하는 거죠
That's all that's going on.
그게 다예요
So that hopefully gives you a sense of of how this works.
그게 어떻게 작동하는지 감을 잡으셨으면 좋겠네요
And I'll delete that.
이건 삭제할게요
Now that's not necessary.
그럴 필요 없어요
The final thing to mention is that there's also a class called opportunity that we define here, which
마지막으로 언급할 것은 기회라는 클래스도 있다는 겁니다 여기서 정의한 것으로
basically is something which has a deal.
기본적으로 거래를 하는 거죠
One of these guys, and also an estimate, which is something later we're going to use when we are estimating
이 중 하나와 견적서요 견적은 나중에 사용할 겁니다 이 거래의 가치를
the value of these deals.
평가할 때요
And then the discount is simply going to be the difference between the deal's price and the estimate
그리고 할인은 단순히 거래 가격과 예상 가격의 차이죠
How much of a discount are we finding that this is being offered?
이 제품은 얼마나 할인받을 수 있나요?
So that is the the setup.
그게 설정이에요
Uh, and with that, let's go back over here.
그럼 다시 이쪽으로 오시죠
Um, so, um, let's fix something there.
그 부분을 좀 고쳐 보죠
Uh, so the, uh, the we've just run, scrape, deal.
그래서 우린 방금 도망치고 긁고 거래했어요
Dot, fetch.
도로시, 가져와요
Uh, we can now look at how many do we have?
이제 몇 개인지 볼 수 있어요
We have 50 deals sitting in deals.
50건의 거래가 성사됐어요
The reason we have 50 deals is because we have, uh, we had five feeds, and we asked for ten deals
50개 세일을 하는 이유는 5개의 피드가 있는데 각각 10개씩 세일을 요구했기 때문이에요
And so that comes to 50, obviously.
그럼 50명이 되는군요
Uh, so that's hopefully what you're expecting to hear.
여러분이 기대하시는 게 그거이길 바라요
Uh, if we look at, uh, um, deal number 44, um, it prints out nicely because you might have seen
거래 번호 44를 보면 프린트가 잘 됐어요 파이썬 마법
I had a, I used one of the Python magic functions to make sure that it was going to print nicely the
기능을 사용했거든요 복제 기능을 잘 프린트하도록요
Um, and so that is what deal number 44 is.
그게 44번 계약 조건이에요
And if we do the full Describe.
전체 묘사를 해 보죠
This is the full bit of information we have about it.
우리가 가진 정보는 이 비트에 다 있어요
It's loads daily deal garage storage bla bla bla bla bla bla bla.
매일 거래되는 차고 저장장치 bla bla bla bla bla bla bla bla bla가 많아요
Choose install to dodge the shipping fee.
배송비를 피하려면 설치를 선택하세요
Uh.
네
So here's the thing.
그런데 말이죠
If you look at that, you'll notice a couple of things about it.
그걸 보면 몇 가지 눈에 띌 거예요
One of them is that the price doesn't come separately in the RSS feed.
그중 하나는 RSS 피드에 가격이 따로 나오지 않는다는 거죠
We don't get the price point, we just get the description of it.
Get it의 가격은 모르고 모양만 알죠
And the other thing you'll see about it is that this one doesn't even have a price.
또 다른 특징은 가격조차 없다는 거예요
It's telling you how much off it is.
얼마나 떨어졌는지 알 수 있죠
It's telling you some things about the free shipping and things like that, but it's not actually giving
무료 배송 같은 건 알려 주지만 이 제품과 관련된 가격은
you a price associated with this product.
알려 주지 않아요
And that's a bore.
그건 지루해요
And so that means that we're not going to be able to always use these properly.
그래서 항상 적절하게 사용할 수 있는 건 아니에요
And we're going to have to do some parsing to figure out what is the actual price that's being offered
파싱 작업을 통해 각각의 항목에 대해 제공되는 실제 가격이 얼마인지
against each of these items.
알아내야 해요
What you'll find if you look at these items is also some of them combine Multiple, uh, things in one,
이 아이템들을 보시면 여러 개를 하나로 묶은 것도 있어요 하나의 카피에요
There's maybe different models of the Apple Watch that are all being offered 20% off.
애플 워치의 다른 모델은 전부 20% 할인을 제공해요
And so trying to digest that and pull out what we want is going to be challenging, very challenging,
따라서 그걸 이해하고 원하는 걸 끌어내는 건 아주 어려울 겁니다 아주 힘들고 그걸 견고한 방식으로
very hard to code that in a way that would be robust.
코드화하는 건 아주 어렵죠
And that's why we need to use a frontier model.
그래서 개척자 모델을 써야 해요
We are going to use GPT four zero to take each of our RSS feeds, scraped deals, and turn that scraped
GPT 40을 이용해서 각 RSS의 피드와 거래를 수집하고 그 거래를 뭔가로
deal into something, which is a good, useful deal for us.
바꿀 겁니다 우리에게 유용한 거래죠
We're actually going to send it all 50 and say, look, we want you to find the best five deals which
50개 모두를 보내 이렇게 말할 겁니다 이 대형 세트에서 가장 명확하게 설명된
are most clearly explained from this big set, pluck them out and summarize it back to us.
최고의 계약 5개를 찾아 그걸 추려내서 요약해 우리에게 보내라고요
And we want that in structured output.
구조화된 출력에서 그걸 원하죠
We're going to tell you what format we want, and we're going to ask you to respond with exactly that
어떤 형식을 원하는지 말하고 정확히 그 형식으로 답변해 달라고 요청할
format.
거예요
And so now you now you've, uh, it's been teed up.
이제 티를 입힌 거예요
You understand what we're trying to accomplish.
우리가 뭘 이루려는 건지 알잖아요
And we're going to do it in the next video.
다음 비디오에서 보여드릴게요